<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Ricardo's Blog</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-02-28T19:50:24-05:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Ricardo Cruz</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>ricardocruz.a89@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started with Ember.js]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2013/12/29/getting-started-with-ember-js/" />
  <id>/2013/12/29/getting-started-with-ember-js</id>
  <published>2013-12-29T15:05:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-29T15:05:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ricardo Cruz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ricardocruz.a89@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;In the summer I started to get interested in learning a MVC Client-side framework, I originally wanted to learn &lt;a href=&quot;http://backbonejs.org/&quot;&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;, but a friend of mine convinced me to learn &lt;a href=&quot;http://emberjs.com/&quot;&gt;Ember.js&lt;/a&gt; instead.
Since one of the developers behind it was part of the Rails Core Team, I knew I would like this framework, so I started to look for some resources to learn Ember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started watching this &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutsplus.com/course/hands-on-emberjs/&quot;&gt;Tutsplus Course&lt;/a&gt; since it consisted on an Ember app with a Rails Backend. Unfortunately, it was hard for me to keep up and understand the material because there was no explanation about everything that was going on or what I had to do so I stopped watching it and stopped trying to learn Ember for a while, since I started to get busy with stuff from work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was until a month ago that I found out that Manning had some books on sale, and I bought a couple, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com/skeie/&quot;&gt;Ember.js in Action&lt;/a&gt;. I started reading it and got through the first chapter and I still didn’t understand much of what was happening, but the book said that was intended, since the first chapter was only an introduction. Before I started reading the second chapter, Codeschool released an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ember.codeschool.com&quot;&gt;Ember.js Course&lt;/a&gt; and I immediately started it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the course (well half of it, since the other half comes out Jan 2014) I can say that it really helped me with the concepts of Ember.js (the Router, Routes, Controllers, Templates, etc) and I would definitely recommend it as a starting point on learning Ember. I even took what I learned on the course and made a little app - &lt;a href=&quot;http://laredo-bridges.heroku.com&quot;&gt;To watch Laredo’s Borders car lines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re interested in learning Ember.js, I believe the resources I mentioned above are pretty good, especially in the following order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeschool Course&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ember.js in action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutsplus Course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, check out Reddit’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/emberjs&quot;&gt;Ember.js Subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, it has some great resources.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2013/12/29/getting-started-with-ember-js/&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Ember.js&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Ricardo Cruz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ricardo's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on December 29, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Github Raw]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/2013/10/04/github-raw/" />
  <id>/2013/10/04/github-raw</id>
  <published>2013-10-04T16:05:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-04T16:05:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ricardo Cruz</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>ricardocruz.a89@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;So a while ago I was playing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net&quot;&gt;JSFiddle&lt;/a&gt; and I wanted to use some jQuery plug-ins directly from Github (via &lt;code&gt;raw.github.com/...&lt;/code&gt;)
but I would get a &lt;code&gt;Refused to execute script from...&lt;/code&gt; error whenever I tried to run the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the files on raw.github are sent with a &lt;code&gt;text/plain&lt;/code&gt; header, making it imposible for sites like JSFiddle and &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;Codepen.io&lt;/a&gt; to execute them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution I found was to basically use a CDN to load the plugin on JSFiddle (for example &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdnjs.com/&quot;&gt;CDNJS&lt;/a&gt;), but the downs of using it is that it doesn’t
have every library  or maybe it has the library, but you need a newer version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A even better solution I found is mentioned on &lt;a href=&quot;http://rawgithub.com&quot;&gt;rawgithub&lt;/a&gt;, that basically consists on deleting the dot on &lt;code&gt;raw.github.com&lt;/code&gt; so it reads like &lt;code&gt;rawgithub.com&lt;/code&gt;. Please use this only for &lt;em&gt;demo&lt;/em&gt; purposes, and not for production, since the site states that it’s slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Credits go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yaypie&quot;&gt;@yaypie&lt;/a&gt; for putting up that information.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2013/10/04/github-raw/&quot;&gt;Github Raw&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Ricardo Cruz at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ricardo's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on October 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
